<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Mentors Archive - Learn with leaders</title>
	<atom:link href="/mentors/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/mentors/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 09:49:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Future Doctors Program</title>
		<link>/mentors/future-doctors-program-2/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=future-doctors-program-2</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 09:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mentors#038;p=14301</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a href="/mentors/future-doctors-program-2/">Future Doctors Program</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a href="/mentors/future-doctors-program-2/">Future Doctors Program</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethan Sayre</title>
		<link>/mentors/ethan-sayre/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=ethan-sayre</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 07:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mentors#038;p=14218</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ethan is passionate about solving problems in the civic action space with technology and the intersection of these two fields. He currently serves as the Director of Technology for Harvard Votes Challenge, where he works to expand civic action on campus. He is also a member of the Harvard Project for International Relations, an organization  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/ethan-sayre/">Ethan Sayre</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ethan is passionate about solving problems in the civic action space with technology and the intersection of these two fields. He currently serves as the Director of Technology for Harvard Votes Challenge, where he works to expand civic action on campus. He is also a member of the Harvard Project for International Relations, an organization that works to bring together global leaders in bi-yearly conferences. In his free time, he loves to hike and be outdoors, travel, and explore new foods and cultures.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/ethan-sayre/">Ethan Sayre</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethan Kelly</title>
		<link>/mentors/ethan-kelly/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=ethan-kelly</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 07:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mentors#038;p=14215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ethan Kelly, is a sophomore from Prince George’s County, Maryland. He is studying government with a focus on American politics. He serves on the Executive Team of the Harvard Kennedy School’s Institute of Politics as the Communications Director, bridging the gap between programming and students. He also serves as a member of the Harvard Public  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/ethan-kelly/">Ethan Kelly</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ethan Kelly, is a sophomore from Prince George’s County, Maryland. He is studying government with a focus on American politics. He serves on the Executive Team of the Harvard Kennedy School’s Institute of Politics as the Communications Director, bridging the gap between programming and students. He also serves as a member of the Harvard Public Opinion Project, an entirely youth-led poll that polls young Americans from ages 18-29, and the Harvard Votes Challenge, an organization focused on increasing voter turnout at Harvard and beyond. Outside of this work, he creates political YouTube videos and works on-and-off campaigns in the field of communications.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/ethan-kelly/">Ethan Kelly</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pratyush Mallik</title>
		<link>/mentors/pratyush-mallik/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=pratyush-mallik</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 07:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mentors#038;p=14212</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pratyush is passionate about developing civic infrastructure, mobilizing voters, and building the future of government and civic technology. He is currently serving as the Vice President of the Institute of Politics at the Harvard Kennedy School. He is also a Senior Product Manager for Harvard Product Lab and a member of SAA (South Asian Association)  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/pratyush-mallik/">Pratyush Mallik</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pratyush is passionate about developing civic infrastructure, mobilizing voters, and building the future of government and civic technology. He is currently serving as the Vice President of the Institute of Politics at the Harvard Kennedy School. He is also a Senior Product Manager for Harvard Product Lab and a member of SAA (South Asian Association) and TAPAS (Task Force for Asian American Progressive Advocacy and Studies). In his free time, you can find him searching for the newest Boston bakeries, watching college football, and practicing calligraphy.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/pratyush-mallik/">Pratyush Mallik</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mitja Bof</title>
		<link>/mentors/mitja-bof/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=mitja-bof</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 07:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mentors#038;p=14209</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>He is majoring in Economics and Statistics, with a minor in Philosophy. He is passionate about the intersection of technology, finance, and growth. He is currently the Director of Finance for the Harvard Project for Asian and International Relations. In the past, he has helped businesses leverage the power of data to optimize their marketing  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/mitja-bof/">Mitja Bof</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He is majoring in Economics and Statistics, with a minor in Philosophy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He is passionate about the intersection of technology, finance, and growth. He is currently the Director of Finance for the Harvard Project for Asian and International Relations. In the past, he has helped businesses leverage the power of data to optimize their marketing efforts and accelerate their growth trajectory. He has also held teaching and research positions on the use of data and tech to solve socio-economics issues. In his free time, you&#8217;ll probably find him running, learning something new, or trying out a new restaurant in town.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/mitja-bof/">Mitja Bof</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adrian Munoz Krans</title>
		<link>/mentors/adrian-munoz-krans/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=adrian-munoz-krans</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mentors#038;p=14167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Adrián Muñoz Krans is a sophomore at Pforzheimer House, studying Social Studies. He currently sits on the board of Harvard Model Congress’s Boston conference and was previously a board member for their San Francisco branch. When he’s not doing model congress, Adrián teaches speech and debate to middle schoolers and has worked alongside the Institute  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/adrian-munoz-krans/">Adrian Munoz Krans</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Adrián Muñoz Krans is a sophomore at Pforzheimer House, studying Social Studies. He currently sits on the board of Harvard Model Congress’s Boston conference and was previously a board member for their San Francisco branch. When he’s not doing model congress, Adrián teaches speech and debate to middle schoolers and has worked alongside the Institute of Politics to advise the city of Cambridge on urban agriculture initiatives. In his free time, Adrián writes poetry, reads fiction, and maintains a daily journal.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/adrian-munoz-krans/">Adrian Munoz Krans</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jonada Shukarasi</title>
		<link>/mentors/jonada-shukarasi/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=jonada-shukarasi</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mentors#038;p=14164</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jonada “Nada” Shukarasi is a sophomore at Harvard University, studying Government and Philosophy with a citation in Russian. She served as Assistant Director for HMUN and HNMUN and was also involved with the Harvard Albanian Students Association. She is a co-founder of Gjejzâ, an award-winning app that offers support and help to Albanian women who  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/jonada-shukarasi/">Jonada Shukarasi</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jonada “Nada” Shukarasi is a sophomore at Harvard University, studying Government and Philosophy with a citation in Russian. She served as Assistant Director for HMUN and HNMUN and was also involved with the Harvard Albanian Students Association. She is a co-founder of Gjejzâ, an award-winning app that offers support and help to Albanian women who experience domestic abuse. She was President of the Debate team and a member of the Albanian Youth Parliament, which has enabled her to be active in political, philosophical and public policy debates.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/jonada-shukarasi/">Jonada Shukarasi</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Theo Harper</title>
		<link>/mentors/theo-harper/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=theo-harper</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mentors#038;p=14161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Theo is a sophomore at Harvard College from London in the United Kingdom. He is particularly interested in international relations and has been involved in MUN since high school traveling with Harvard’s competitive team and working on both Harvard’s high school and college MUN conferences. He chairs Harvard’s Political Union debating pressing (and not-so-pressing) issues.  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/theo-harper/">Theo Harper</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Theo is a sophomore at Harvard College from London in the United Kingdom. He is particularly interested in international relations and has been involved in MUN since high school traveling with Harvard’s competitive team and working on both Harvard’s high school and college MUN conferences. He chairs Harvard’s Political Union debating pressing (and not-so-pressing) issues. He also works on the Harvard Undergraduate Foreign Policy Initiative and volunteers with one of Harvard’s teaching programs helping to educate middle schoolers in their civic rights.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/theo-harper/">Theo Harper</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mohammed Maarouf</title>
		<link>/mentors/mohammed-maarouf/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=mohammed-maarouf</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mentors#038;p=14158</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Mohammed Maarouf is a third-year student at Harvard University studying Applied Math in Economics and Computer Science. He has been involved with the Harvard Financial Analysts Club, Harvard Real Estate Investment Group, and Harvard Futsal Club. In high school, his biggest passion was Speech &amp; Debate where he competed state-wide and nationally. A resident of  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/mohammed-maarouf/">Mohammed Maarouf</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mohammed Maarouf is a third-year student at Harvard University studying Applied Math in Economics and Computer Science. He has been involved with the Harvard Financial Analysts Club, Harvard Real Estate Investment Group, and Harvard Futsal Club. In high school, his biggest passion was Speech &amp; Debate where he competed state-wide and nationally. A resident of Southern California, he&#8217;s a huge fan of the beach, playing soccer, and an adrenaline junkie– he’s even been on Formula Rossa!</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/mohammed-maarouf/">Mohammed Maarouf</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saaim Khan</title>
		<link>/mentors/saaim-khan/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=saaim-khan</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 08:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mentors#038;p=14048</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Saaim is a junior at Harvard College studying Human Developmental and Regenerative Biology. His keen interest lies in examining biological concepts through diverse scientific lenses and is dedicated to using technology as a means to improve the healthcare and education systems.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/saaim-khan/">Saaim Khan</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Saaim is a junior at Harvard College studying Human Developmental and Regenerative Biology. His keen interest lies in examining biological concepts through diverse scientific lenses and is dedicated to using technology as a means to improve the healthcare and education systems.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="/mentors/saaim-khan/">Saaim Khan</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
