<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Media blog Archive - Learn with leaders</title>
	<atom:link href="/blogmedia/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blogmedia/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 07:22:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Expanding Horizons &#038; Breaking Stereotypes:  My Journey through the Public Speaking Masterclass by Hala Osman</title>
		<link>/blogmedia/expanding-horizons-breaking-stereotypes-my-journey-through-the-public-speaking-masterclass-by-hala-osman/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=expanding-horizons-breaking-stereotypes-my-journey-through-the-public-speaking-masterclass-by-hala-osman</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 07:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mediablog#038;p=13746</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hala Munira Osman, Grade 10, UAE ------ Expressing my ideas has always been a challenge for me. When I stand in front of a group or a class, my words often escape me, leaving me stumbling and unsure. However, those moments of uncertainty are now a thing of the past. My perspective shifted after participating  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/expanding-horizons-breaking-stereotypes-my-journey-through-the-public-speaking-masterclass-by-hala-osman/">Expanding Horizons &#038; Breaking Stereotypes:  My Journey through the Public Speaking Masterclass by Hala Osman</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-13747" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Hala-Osman.png" alt="" width="191" height="260" /></span></p>
<p><b>Hala Munira Osman,</b><b><br />
</b><b>Grade 10,</b><b><br />
</b><b>UAE</b></p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Expressing my ideas has always been a challenge for me. When I stand in front of a group or a class, my words often escape me, leaving me stumbling and unsure. However, those moments of uncertainty are now a thing of the past. My perspective shifted after participating in the Public Speaking Masterclass by Learn with Leaders. This experience not only helped me realize that I wasn&#8217;t alone in my struggles but also equipped me with the tools to overcome them.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During the masterclass, I hung onto every word the speaker shared, eagerly applying her insights to my own experiences. I marveled at her unwavering confidence as she addressed us, her words flowing effortlessly. Comparing her poise to my own tendencies, I couldn&#8217;t help but acknowledge the room for improvement in my own public speaking skills.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The masterclass proved to be a treasure trove of knowledge, offering a wealth of practical tips that I intend to integrate into my future presentations. The speaker explored various types of public speaking, including persuasive and ceremonial styles, emphasizing the importance of tailoring each approach to suit the audience. This concept resonated with me, highlighting the significance of capturing and maintaining the audience&#8217;s attention. Beyond the speaker&#8217;s insights, I found myself drawn to the global online audience. Witnessing the diversity and inclusivity of the participants was captivating. Interacting with peers my age from around the world, all striving to enhance their communication skills, was truly inspiring.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a young person exposed to a myriad of cultures and languages, I am now more determined than ever to speak confidently about my beliefs and challenge prevailing stereotypes, particularly those perpetuated by the media. This masterclass opened my eyes to the power of effective communication. It provided me with the tools to discern different speech styles, select the most suitable one for a given situation, and connect with diverse audiences.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In conclusion, my journey through the Public Speaking Masterclass was transformative. I emerged with newfound confidence and a heightened sense of purpose. Armed with a deeper understanding of communication dynamics, I am eager to embark on a path where my words can foster understanding, break barriers, and effect positive change.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/expanding-horizons-breaking-stereotypes-my-journey-through-the-public-speaking-masterclass-by-hala-osman/">Expanding Horizons &#038; Breaking Stereotypes:  My Journey through the Public Speaking Masterclass by Hala Osman</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Carla&#8217;s Journey: Empowering Youth, Advocating for Change, and Mastering the Art of Debate</title>
		<link>/blogmedia/carlas-journey-empowering-youth-advocating-for-change-and-mastering-the-art-of-debate/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=carlas-journey-empowering-youth-advocating-for-change-and-mastering-the-art-of-debate</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 09:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mediablog#038;p=12914</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Carla Bartoli, a passionate and ambitious Grade 11 student from the International School of Palermo, Italy, discovered her love for leadership, public speaking, and global politics in a small town in Sicily. Despite limited opportunities in her hometown, Carla's determination to make a difference led her to pursue various initiatives and advocate for causes close  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/carlas-journey-empowering-youth-advocating-for-change-and-mastering-the-art-of-debate/">Carla&#8217;s Journey: Empowering Youth, Advocating for Change, and Mastering the Art of Debate</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="wp-image-12916 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.52-PM.jpeg" alt="" width="338" height="225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.52-PM-200x133.jpeg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.52-PM-300x200.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.52-PM-400x267.jpeg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.52-PM-600x400.jpeg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.52-PM-768x512.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.52-PM-800x533.jpeg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.52-PM-1024x682.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.52-PM-1200x800.jpeg 1200w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.52-PM-1536x1023.jpeg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.52-PM.jpeg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 338px) 100vw, 338px" />Carla Bartoli, a passionate and ambitious Grade 11 student from the International School of Palermo, Italy, discovered her love for leadership, public speaking, and global politics in a small town in Sicily. Despite limited opportunities in her hometown, Carla&#8217;s determination to make a difference led her to pursue various initiatives and advocate for causes close to her heart. One such cause is the participation of young women in politics, which she believes is essential for shaping a better future. Let&#8217;s delve into Carla&#8217;s journey, her accomplishments, and the invaluable lessons she learned along the way.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>The Debating Boot Camp Experience:</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Carla had the privilege of attending the Debating Boot Camp by Harvard Student Agencies. This experience was instrumental in honing her debating skills, gaining global perspectives, and meeting like-minded individuals from around the world. The program emphasized the importance of research, constructing compelling arguments, and effectively countering opponents&#8217; claims. The skills Carla acquired during the boot camp have since helped her excel in debates and discussions, both academically and in advocacy work.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Carla interacting with Enrico Letta, ex-Italian prime minister and ex-secretary of the democratic party in Italy</b></p>
<p><b>Discovering a Passion for Advocacy:</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Growing up in Favara, a town near Agrigento, Sicily, Carla cherished the warm weather, friendly people, and close-knit community. However, she soon realized that her town lacked opportunities for personal and intellectual growth. Eager to expand her horizons, Carla made the bold decision to move abroad and pursue an exchange program in France. This experience sparked her interest in politics, international relations, and women&#8217;s empowerment.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>The Power of Everyday Politics:</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Carla firmly believes that one doesn&#8217;t need to be a politician to make a difference in politics. She learned that politics encompasses every aspect of our lives and that everyone has the power to effect change. Carla shares a heartwarming example from her own life, where she organized a successful fundraising campaign to help Ukrainian refugees during the Russia-Ukraine conflict. By leveraging social media and mobilizing the local community, she managed to raise funds and arrange transportation for these displaced individuals, ultimately connecting them with Sicilian families.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-12917 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.54-PM.jpeg" alt="" width="333" height="216" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.54-PM-200x130.jpeg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.54-PM-300x194.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.54-PM-400x259.jpeg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.54-PM-600x389.jpeg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.54-PM-768x498.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.54-PM-800x518.jpeg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.54-PM-1024x663.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/WhatsApp-Image-2023-07-03-at-1.21.54-PM.jpeg 1170w" sizes="(max-width: 333px) 100vw, 333px" />Motivating Others to Take Action:</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to motivating others to take action, Carla emphasizes the importance of having a support system. Her friends and family played a crucial role in encouraging her to pursue her dreams and make a positive impact. Carla&#8217;s advice to young students is to not be afraid of failure and to keep trying. She believes that failure is just a stepping stone toward success and that perseverance is key. By learning from those who excel and continuously challenge themselves, anyone can contribute meaningfully to society.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Overcoming Challenges:</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Following her dreams wasn&#8217;t without challenges for Carla. Moving abroad and living independently presented difficulties, particularly the sense of loneliness and the absence of an adult figure for guidance. Yet, Carla&#8217;s unwavering determination and the support of her loved ones helped her overcome these obstacles. She advises others to embrace challenges as opportunities for personal growth and learning. Carla&#8217;s mother instilled in her the belief that learning never stops, and even when surrounded by more accomplished people, there is always something to be gained.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Carla&#8217;s journey serves as an inspiration to youth worldwide, showcasing the power of determination, compassion, and the pursuit of knowledge. From her small town in Sicily to international platforms, she continues to advocate for women&#8217;s participation in politics, raise awareness about global issues, and empower others to take action. Calra&#8217;s story is a testament to the fact that age and circumstances should never limit one&#8217;s ability to create positive change.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/carlas-journey-empowering-youth-advocating-for-change-and-mastering-the-art-of-debate/">Carla&#8217;s Journey: Empowering Youth, Advocating for Change, and Mastering the Art of Debate</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Masterclass on Entrepreneurial Thinking &#038; Creativity &#8211; By Leen Khaled Mansour Awamleh, Jordan</title>
		<link>/blogmedia/masterclass-on-entrepreneurial-thinking-creativity-by-leen-khaled-mansour-awamleh-jordan/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=masterclass-on-entrepreneurial-thinking-creativity-by-leen-khaled-mansour-awamleh-jordan</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 13:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mediablog#038;p=12671</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I have always been passionate about entrepreneurship. During the Masterclass on Entrepreneurial Thinking and Creativity, I learned the fundamentals of starting a business, including how to develop an idea and conduct market research. During our meeting, I learned the fundamentals of starting a business, including how to develop an idea, conduct market research to identify  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/masterclass-on-entrepreneurial-thinking-creativity-by-leen-khaled-mansour-awamleh-jordan/">Masterclass on Entrepreneurial Thinking &#038; Creativity &#8211; By Leen Khaled Mansour Awamleh, Jordan</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-12672 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/student-jordan.png" alt="" width="137" height="247" />I have always been passionate about entrepreneurship. During the Masterclass on Entrepreneurial Thinking and Creativity, I learned the fundamentals of starting a business, including how to develop an idea and conduct market research. During our meeting, I learned the fundamentals of starting a business, including how to develop an idea, conduct market research to identify competitors, create a unique value proposition that sets us apart from our competitors, and how to attract sponsors and supporters. We also discussed marketing strategies, including the use of social media platforms and influencers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">While social media marketing can be effective in the short term, I believe that its impact may be fleeting. In the fashion industry, for example, we can see how users of social media constantly try to keep up with what is fashionable, causing trends to come and go quickly. To succeed in the competitive business world, it is important to create a marketing strategy that is long-lasting and sustainable, so that influencers and celebrities continue to promote your product or service. This will help you stay on course and avoid falling behind, as everyone is vying to become a leader in their respective industries.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/masterclass-on-entrepreneurial-thinking-creativity-by-leen-khaled-mansour-awamleh-jordan/">Masterclass on Entrepreneurial Thinking &#038; Creativity &#8211; By Leen Khaled Mansour Awamleh, Jordan</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Leadership Journey:  Riddhi Javali, Grade 12, Bengaluru, India</title>
		<link>/blogmedia/my-leadership-journey-riddhi-javali-grade-12-bengaluru-india/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=my-leadership-journey-riddhi-javali-grade-12-bengaluru-india</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 06:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mediablog#038;p=12373</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Scholars in Communication Program played a significant role in enhancing my communication skills and boosting my confidence. These skills proved to be invaluable in my journey of establishing a non-profit organization, Project Repeat.   As the founder of Project Repeat, my passion for helping others led me to start this initiative. The government's decision  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/my-leadership-journey-riddhi-javali-grade-12-bengaluru-india/">My Leadership Journey:  Riddhi Javali, Grade 12, Bengaluru, India</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Scholars in Communication Program played a significant role in enhancing my communication skills and boosting my confidence. These skills proved to be invaluable in my journey of establishing a non-profit organization, <strong>Project Repeat</strong>.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As the founder of Project Repeat, my passion for helping others led me to start this initiative. The government&#8217;s decision to halt the provision of free sanitary napkins to schoolgirls during the pandemic prompted me to take action. I recognized that poor menstrual hygiene is a severe problem, particularly for schoolgirls in rural areas. It is also a significant factor contributing to adolescent girls dropping out of school.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My non-profit organization aims to provide free sustainable and eco-friendly menstrual hygiene options to government school girls in India. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We offer reusable cloth pads that are safe for </span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-12377 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-1.jpg" alt="" width="484" height="272" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-1-200x113.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-1-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-1-400x225.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-1-600x338.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-1-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-1-800x450.jpg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-1-1200x675.jpg 1200w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-1-1536x864.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-1.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 484px) 100vw, 484px" />the body and the environment and can be used for up to 5 years. Although this may seem like a simple idea, executing it was not easy. I had to reach out to government officials and talk to students who consider menstruation to be a taboo topic.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Menstrual hygiene carries a stigma in our society, but my family&#8217;s open-mindedness inspired and aided me in starting this organization. Initially, girls in rural areas were hesitant to discuss menstrual hygiene, but as they began to open up, I could talk to them and create awareness about sustainable menstruation and menstruation in general.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As part of Project Repeat, I visit government schools in Karnataka to provide free reusable cloth pad kits and educate girls about sustainable menstruation. To date, I have visited ten schools and distributed kits to about 400 girls. Initially, I used my own money to purchase the cloth pad kits, but I began receiving funds from friends and family as the initiative gained momentum.</span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-12378 alignright" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-4.jpg" alt="" width="550" height="310" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-4-200x113.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-4-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-4-400x225.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-4-600x338.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-4-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-4-800x450.jpg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-4-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-4-1200x675.jpg 1200w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-4-1536x864.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/04/PR-4.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In conclusion, through my experience with Project Repeat, I have learned that small actions can lead to significant changes. With the help of communication skills and confidence gained from the Scholars in Com</span>munication Program, I was able to make a difference in the lives of girls in rural areas and address a critical problem that is often overlooked.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/my-leadership-journey-riddhi-javali-grade-12-bengaluru-india/">My Leadership Journey:  Riddhi Javali, Grade 12, Bengaluru, India</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Acing your Public Speaking and Delivering an Impactful Speech</title>
		<link>/blogmedia/acing-your-public-speaking-and-delivering-an-impactful-speech/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=acing-your-public-speaking-and-delivering-an-impactful-speech</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 12:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mediablog#038;p=11940</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We know how nerve-wracking it can be to stand in front of an audience and deliver a speech. However, with just the right preparation and mindset, you can deliver an impactful speech that leaves a lasting impression on your audience.    Whether you are presenting a project to your classmates or delivering a graduation speech,  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/acing-your-public-speaking-and-delivering-an-impactful-speech/">Acing your Public Speaking and Delivering an Impactful Speech</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We know how nerve-wracking it can be to stand in front of an audience and deliver a speech. However, with just the right preparation and mindset, you can deliver an impactful speech that leaves a lasting impression on your audience. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whether you are presenting a project to your classmates or delivering a graduation speech, these five tips will help you become a more confident and effective public speaker.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Know your audience: </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You have an impressive speech penned down, and an aesthetically pleasing presentation ready and you are all confident to go out on the stage and impress your audience, but once you are in the middle of the speech, you realize your audience is distracted? They are not interested in hearing what you have to say. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why did this happen? Probably because the topic you chose to speak about did not relate to your audience.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before you begin writing your speech, it is essential to know your audience. Their age, interests, and level of knowledge will help you decide the course of the topic you will discuss. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This will help you tailor your speech to their needs and ensure that they stay engaged throughout your presentation.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start with a hook: A powerful opening can captivate your audience&#8217;s attention and set the tone for the rest of your speech. Consider starting with a surprising statistic, a compelling story, or a thought-provoking question. This will help you grab your audience&#8217;s attention and encourage them to listen to what you have to say.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Practice, practice, practice: The key to delivering a confident and effective speech is practice. Rehearse your speech multiple times, and consider recording yourself to identify areas where you can improve. This will help you feel more comfortable and prepared when it&#8217;s time to deliver your speech.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use visuals: Visual aids can help illustrate your points and make your speech more engaging. Consider using PowerPoint slides, props, or videos to support your message. However, be careful not to rely too heavily on visual aids and make sure they enhance rather than distract from your speech.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">End with a call to action: A strong conclusion can leave a lasting impression on your audience and encourage them to take action. Consider ending your speech with a call to action, such as asking your audience to sign a petition or volunteer for a cause. This will help your audience feel inspired and motivated to make a difference.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Delivering an impactful speech takes time, practice, and careful consideration. By knowing your audience, starting with a hook, practicing your speech, using visuals, and ending with a call to action, you can become a more confident and effective public speaker. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learn with Leaders is offering a virtual Masterclass on the Art of Public Speaking for Personal &amp; Professional Success, led by <strong>Jonada Shukarasi</strong> for school students, covering the basics of public speaking, overcoming stage fright, structuring a speech &amp; engaging with an audience. Students will gain skills to succeed in various contexts, such as academic presentations, college admissions, and even job interviews. </span></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/acing-your-public-speaking-and-delivering-an-impactful-speech/">Acing your Public Speaking and Delivering an Impactful Speech</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Ways to be an Effective Leader by Theo Harper</title>
		<link>/blogmedia/5-ways-to-be-an-effective-leader-by-theo-harper/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=5-ways-to-be-an-effective-leader-by-theo-harper</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 07:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mediablog#038;p=11737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Leadership is vital in the modern world - from the smallest team to the largest company, being able to take the lead is vital to being able to implement your vision of how to make a difference. Here are 5 ways to be an effective leader:   Be prepared: If you have an idea of  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/5-ways-to-be-an-effective-leader-by-theo-harper/">5 Ways to be an Effective Leader by Theo Harper</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Leadership is vital in the modern world &#8211; from the smallest team to the largest company, being able to take the lead is vital to being able to implement your vision of how to make a difference. Here are 5 ways to be an effective leader:</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Be prepared:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> If you have an idea of what will happen when you enter the room, it can be much easier to have a strategy. Knowing what the likely outcomes are and how to manipulate them makes it much easier to lead the group in the direction you want.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Take the initiative:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Sometimes, you have to be the one to kickstart things into action &#8211; don’t be scared, it’s an opportunity for you to gain the advantage and take control of the situation to achieve what you want.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Public speaking:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> It runs against everything our psychology trains us to do, but being able to speak publicly is a vital skill to being able to win over and lead a group no matter the size.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Be positive and confident:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> People take their cues from the leader. If you are upbeat, clear and confident, they will follow you with energy and excitement. If you lack confidence, they will too.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Criticism is fine:</b> Most importantly, be able to take criticism. People don’t like leaders in ivory towers. We all make mistakes, and it is really important to be able to accept that and change the way we are occasionally to be a good leader.</li>
</ol>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/5-ways-to-be-an-effective-leader-by-theo-harper/">5 Ways to be an Effective Leader by Theo Harper</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get Ready to Level Up Your Writing Skills with Research Writing!</title>
		<link>/blogmedia/get-ready-to-level-up-your-writing-skills-with-research-writing/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=get-ready-to-level-up-your-writing-skills-with-research-writing</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 10:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mediablog#038;p=11748</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As a high school student, you're about to embark on a journey that will take your writing skills to the next level. Research writing assignments are a common part of your classes and they're more than just boring essays. These assignments are your chance to show off your critical thinking skills, improve your writing abilities,  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/get-ready-to-level-up-your-writing-skills-with-research-writing/">Get Ready to Level Up Your Writing Skills with Research Writing!</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a high school student, you&#8217;re about to embark on a journey that will take your writing skills to the next level. Research writing assignments are a common part of your classes and they&#8217;re more than just boring essays. These assignments are your chance to show off your critical thinking skills, improve your writing abilities, and learn about new and exciting topics.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here&#8217;s what you&#8217;ll need to do to ace your research writing assignments:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Become a Detective</strong>: Researching is the first step to writing a research paper, and it&#8217;s a blast! You get to be like Sherlock Holmes, searching for the best sources to help you write your paper. But, be careful! Not all sources are created equal. You&#8217;ll need to learn how to identify reliable sources, check their credibility, and combine information from multiple sources to create a solid paper.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Think Outside the Box</strong>: Research writing requires you to analyze and interpret information, form opinions, and draw conclusions based on evidence. This is where you get to show off your critical thinking skills! You&#8217;ll learn how to think beyond what you already know and make informed decisions.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Write Like a Pro</strong>: Research writing is an opportunity for you to hone your writing abilities. You&#8217;ll learn how to write clearly and concisely, and how to present your ideas in a way that&#8217;s convincing and engaging.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Get Organized</strong>: Research papers can get messy, but with the right tools, you&#8217;ll be able to keep your thoughts and ideas in order. You&#8217;ll learn how to create an outline, write a thesis statement, and organize your paper into neat and tidy paragraphs.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Time Management</strong>: Research writing takes time and effort, but with proper planning and execution, you&#8217;ll be able to get it done in no time. You&#8217;ll learn how to manage your time effectively, set goals, and work consistently towards meeting your deadlines.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Do you identify as a high school student who loves to know the &#8220;WHY&#8221; of things, deep diving into the details and complexities of topics, asking questions, and seeking answers through various sources? Learn with Leaders has just the perfect opportunity for you</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Led and guided by qualified mentors from Ivy League Universities, the Research Scholars Program is uniquely designed for high school students to guide them through the art of research and writing research papers. </span>Through the course of 8 weekends, the students deep dive into a wide range of areas like STEM, Art, Humanities, Entrepreneurship, Law, and many more with a focus on developing critical thinking and analytical skills.  The program also gives the students a chance to author a research paper with the possibility of getting it published.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>With this incredible opportunity, the students will gain a competitive edge when applying to their dream colleges and Ivy League Universities! To know more, head to <a href="/certificate_programs/research-scholars-program-dec/"><strong>The Research Scholars Page</strong></a>!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In conclusion, research writing is an exciting and challenging experience that will help you develop your writing skills and critical thinking abilities. With these new skills, you&#8217;ll be ready for anything that comes your way in your academic and professional life. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>Get ready to dive into the world of research writing and let the fun begin!</em></strong></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/get-ready-to-level-up-your-writing-skills-with-research-writing/">Get Ready to Level Up Your Writing Skills with Research Writing!</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sustainability for Teenagers: Why It Matters and How You Can Make a Difference – By Aliyah Omran</title>
		<link>/blogmedia/sustainability-for-teenagers-why-it-matters-and-how-you-can-make-a-difference-by-aliyah-omran/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=sustainability-for-teenagers-why-it-matters-and-how-you-can-make-a-difference-by-aliyah-omran</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 19:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mediablog#038;p=8544</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>  As a teenager, you may feel like your voice and actions don't have much of an impact on the world. But when it comes to sustainability, every little bit helps. And as a generation that will bear the brunt of climate change, it's more important than ever for teenagers to understand the importance of  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/sustainability-for-teenagers-why-it-matters-and-how-you-can-make-a-difference-by-aliyah-omran/">Sustainability for Teenagers: Why It Matters and How You Can Make a Difference – By Aliyah Omran</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-8545" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/gx-sustainability-in-retail-header-1_1200-x-627-300x157.jpeg" alt="" width="505" height="264" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/gx-sustainability-in-retail-header-1_1200-x-627-200x105.jpeg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/gx-sustainability-in-retail-header-1_1200-x-627-300x157.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/gx-sustainability-in-retail-header-1_1200-x-627-400x209.jpeg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/gx-sustainability-in-retail-header-1_1200-x-627-600x314.jpeg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/gx-sustainability-in-retail-header-1_1200-x-627-768x401.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/gx-sustainability-in-retail-header-1_1200-x-627-800x418.jpeg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/gx-sustainability-in-retail-header-1_1200-x-627-1024x535.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/gx-sustainability-in-retail-header-1_1200-x-627.jpeg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 505px) 100vw, 505px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As a teenager, you may feel like your voice and actions don&#8217;t have much of an impact on the world. But when it comes to sustainability, every little bit helps. And as a generation that will bear the brunt of climate change, it&#8217;s more important than ever for teenagers to understand the importance of sustainability and how they can make a difference.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>First and foremost, sustainability is about protecting our planet for future generations. Climate change, pollution, and overconsumption are all major threats to the environment, and if we don&#8217;t take action now, the consequences will be dire. But by making sustainable choices, we can reduce our impact on the earth and ensure that there is a healthy planet for our children and grandchildren to inherit.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Sustainability is also about social justice. Climate change and environmental degradation disproportionately affect marginalized communities, and by working towards sustainability, we can help to create a more equitable world.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>But perhaps most importantly, sustainability is about creating a better future for ourselves. By living sustainably, we can enjoy clean air and water, protect biodiversity, and have access to resources for generations to come.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So, what can teenagers do to make a difference? There are plenty of small actions you can take to reduce your environmental impact. Here are a few ideas to get you started:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reduce, reuse, and recycle</strong>: This is one of the most basic ways to be sustainable. By cutting down on waste and using things for as long as possible, you can help to conserve resources and reduce pollution.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Use public transportation, carpool, or bike</strong>: Transportation is one of the biggest contributors to greenhouse gas emissions, so cutting down on your car use can have a big impact.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Eat less meat</strong>: Animal agriculture is a major source of greenhouse gas emissions and deforestation. By eating less meat, you can help to reduce your impact on the environment.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Use energy-efficient appliances and light bulbs</strong>: These use less energy and save you money on your utility bills.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Support sustainable brands and products</strong>: When you buy products, look for those that are made from sustainable materials or produced in a sustainable way.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Remember, sustainability is not a one-time action, it is a lifestyle that requires continuous effort. As a teenager, you have the power to make a difference and shape the future. By taking small actions today, you can help to create a more sustainable and just world for tomorrow.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/sustainability-for-teenagers-why-it-matters-and-how-you-can-make-a-difference-by-aliyah-omran/">Sustainability for Teenagers: Why It Matters and How You Can Make a Difference – By Aliyah Omran</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Ways to Create a Mental Action Plan – By Akshada Dake</title>
		<link>/blogmedia/3-ways-to-create-a-mental-action-plan-by-akshada-dake/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=3-ways-to-create-a-mental-action-plan-by-akshada-dake</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 10:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mediablog#038;p=8465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Don’t fall into the clutches of procrastination, use your google calendar. Schedule your assignments by their due dates and priorities. Don’t be generic, be specific. Make sure to add descriptions to your tasks and add the following: due date, task descriptor, and the time needed, take note of extracurriculars that affect completion. When you do  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/3-ways-to-create-a-mental-action-plan-by-akshada-dake/">3 Ways to Create a Mental Action Plan – By Akshada Dake</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
<li>Don’t fall into the clutches of procrastination, use your google calendar. Schedule your assignments by their due dates and priorities. Don’t be generic, be specific. Make sure to add descriptions to your tasks and add the following: due date, task descriptor, and the time needed, take note of extracurriculars that affect completion. When you do this long enough, you’ll be able to identify these qualities without having to write them down.</li>
<li>Organize your information. If it’s a writing task or requires research, keep your sources in a document. Organization is key. Organized information can be less overwhelming and eliminates procrastination.</li>
<li>Make a productivity chart. This will help you identify your strengths and weaknesses in terms of self-management. For 2 weeks, not during exam clutch time, observe yourself and the general pattern of your overall productivity and take notes on a spreadsheet. It helps generate a schedule taking into account your procrastination, motivation, and possible uncertainties. It doesn’t have to be detailed, take a look at my first motivation chart.</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-8471 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Time-Management-300x167.png" alt="" width="300" height="167" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Time-Management-200x112.png 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Time-Management-300x167.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Time-Management-400x223.png 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Time-Management-600x335.png 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Time-Management.png 602w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/3-ways-to-create-a-mental-action-plan-by-akshada-dake/">3 Ways to Create a Mental Action Plan – By Akshada Dake</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Metamorphosis’- ‘From a Shy Girl to a Theatre Actor and Changemaker’ – Prakriti Asthana</title>
		<link>/blogmedia/metamorphosis-from-a-shy-girl-to-a-theatre-actor-and-changemaker/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=metamorphosis-from-a-shy-girl-to-a-theatre-actor-and-changemaker</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 13:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=mediablog#038;p=8454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I was born and brought up in a small but beautiful town in India called Chandigarh. I still remember when I was 6 or 7 years old, a few family friends had come over. I hid behind my father as if greeting them back to their “Hello” was akin to saying “eat me” to a  [...]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/metamorphosis-from-a-shy-girl-to-a-theatre-actor-and-changemaker/">Metamorphosis’- ‘From a Shy Girl to a Theatre Actor and Changemaker’ – Prakriti Asthana</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-8456 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/WhatsApp-Image-2022-12-29-at-6.53.13-PM-298x300.jpeg" alt="" width="298" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/WhatsApp-Image-2022-12-29-at-6.53.13-PM-66x66.jpeg 66w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/12/WhatsApp-Image-2022-12-29-at-6.53.13-PM-150x150.jpeg 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/12/WhatsApp-Image-2022-12-29-at-6.53.13-PM-200x201.jpeg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/12/WhatsApp-Image-2022-12-29-at-6.53.13-PM-298x300.jpeg 298w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/12/WhatsApp-Image-2022-12-29-at-6.53.13-PM-400x403.jpeg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/12/WhatsApp-Image-2022-12-29-at-6.53.13-PM.jpeg 565w" sizes="(max-width: 298px) 100vw, 298px" /></p>
<p>I was born and brought up in a small but beautiful town in India called Chandigarh. I still remember when I was 6 or 7 years old, a few family friends had come over. I hid behind my father as if greeting them back to their “Hello” was akin to saying “eat me” to a lion!</p>
<p>Post that embarrassing incident, my parents took it on themselves to make me confident to face the public, so they enrolled me into a summer camp in 2014. It was a theatre summer camp where everyone had to get up on stage, face an audience of 20-30 kids every single day and perform. It was a complete nightmare, but the best part was stepping into the shoes of my character and forgetting who I was. By the end of the year, I was cast as the main character in the Academy’s final production.<b></b></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As 6 years passed, I grew into being more confident, expressive, and respectful of the art. Theatre helped me in ways, nothing could, but then there came along yet another feather to my Metamorphosis Tale. <span style="font-weight: 400;">One day I was in my Education Counsellor’s office when she saw a program- TWF TAKE THE WORLD FORWARD by Harvard Model Congress San Francisco and Harvard Student Agencies.</span> She hesitated for a second then asked me, “Would you want to apply for something different than what you usually do?” I didn’t understand and inquired more about the program, when I heard about it, I was amazed with what the organization, ‘Learn with Leaders’ was doing, and deeply wanted to be a part of it, I completed my application in a day, and got selected!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>My first project happened with my team, which consisted of people from Argentina, Romania, Netherlands, and little did I know all of them would become such close friends to me! This fellowship helped me even more by teaching me diversity, how different cultures, routines, and rituals are present in different parts of the world. It’s amazing to see how people with such different backgrounds, different dialects come together and form sustainable ideas. Currently, I’m in the second part of my fellowship and what can I say? I am loving each and every minute of it.”</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As part of her Take the World Forward Fellowship Project, Prakriti wants to make Menstrual Health &amp; Hygiene resources easily accessible to teenage girls in schools.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blogmedia/metamorphosis-from-a-shy-girl-to-a-theatre-actor-and-changemaker/">Metamorphosis’- ‘From a Shy Girl to a Theatre Actor and Changemaker’ – Prakriti Asthana</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Learn with leaders</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
